SOUVIK SARKAR.

Thinker — Builder — Communicator

sounix000@gmail.com ◊ (+91) 6360229130 ◊ sounix000.github.io

OVERVIEW

Technical Writer with 8 years of experience documenting software and APIs for developers and administrators, backed by 4 years of experience as a developer. I develop technical content for an optimal developer experience, using docs-as-code, modular documentation, and open-source tools.

SKILLS

Programming C/C++, Python, Bash
Markup AsciiDoc, DocBook XML
Deployment Docker, Kubernetes
Cloud Google Cloud Platform
Images/Diagrams Inkscape, Mermaid.js
Code/Text Editors VS Code, Vim
Projects and Analytics JIRA, Google Sheets

EMPLOYMENT

SUSE March 2023 - Present

Senior Technical Writer

- · Own the SUSE Linux Enterprise guides for performance tuning, virtualization, and compliance certifications.
- · Contribute to transitioning from monolithic guides to topic-based modular documentation for SUSE Linux Enterprise.
- · Collaborate with engineers, release managers, and product managers to realign the SUSE Linux Enterprise documentation with the upstream OpenSUSE documentation.
- · Interface with the support engineering team to reinforce existing documentation and create clientspecific knowledge base articles.
- · Participate in peer reviews and mentor new technical writers in the team.
- · Technologies/Tools: SUSE Linux Enterprise, OpenSUSE Leap, Bash, Python, DocBook XML, AsciiDoc, GitHub, VS Code, SUSE style guide, JIRA, Confluence Wiki, Slack.

Red Hat November 2020–March 2023

Senior Technical Writer

- · Lead documentation efforts for OpenShift CI/CD Pipelines, including triaging issues, creating documentation plans, and deciding content strategy.
- · Participated in peer reviews of documents for other products and mentored new technical writers in the team.
- · Collaborated with content strategists and product managers to realign product documentation with upstream documentation.
- · Interfaced with the support engineering team to reinforce existing documentation and create clientspecific knowledge-base articles.
- · Data analyzed to improve documentation coverage, flow, architecture, findability, and accessibility.
- · Technologies/Tools: Fedora Linux, Docker, Kubernetes, Golang, Node.js, Bash, AsciiDoc, Markdown, Lucidchart, GitHub, VS Code, Atom, IBM style guide, JIRA, Trello, Tableau, Google Sheets, Slack.

Ribbon Communications

January 2019–November 2020

Senior Technical Writer

- · Lead documentation efforts for SBC Core, resulting in improved customer satisfaction ratings.
- · Developed documents such as CLI reference and REST API user guide.
- · Participated in peer reviews of documents for other products and mentored new technical writers in the team.
- · Collaborated to revamp the internal style guide for easier onboarding of new technical writers.
- · Technologies/Tools: Proprietary networking and telecom hardware, Debian Linux, C++, Bash, Open-Stack, AWS, Confluence Wiki, Snagit, Microsoft style guide, JIRA.

FusionCharts (Infosoft Global Pvt. Ltd.)

March 2018–January 2019

Technical Content Writer

- · Developed and reviewed sample applications, code snippets, and content for developer documentation.
- · Implemented automation scripts to improve the operational efficiency of pre-release workflows.
- · Worked with the engineering and marketing teams to create and publish technical articles on third-party websites and blogs.
- · Technologies/Tools: macOS, JavaScript (Node.js, Vue.js, React.js), Markdown, Lucidchart, Google Style Guide, GitHub, Trello, Slack.

Tata Elxsi June 2016–March 2018

Consultant Technical Writer

Contractor for Ribbon Communications

- · Created and maintained Quick Start tutorials, API guides, User guides, and Release Notes.
- · Technologies/Tools: Proprietary networking and telecom hardware, Debian Linux, Confluence Wiki, Snagit, Microsoft style guide, JIRA.

Agaze Technologies

September 2015–May 2016

Software Engineer

- · Developed internal and client-facing applications, focusing on back-end implementation.
- · <u>Technologies/Tools</u>: Ubuntu Linux, Python (Django, Flask), PostgreSQL, JavaScript (Node.js, React.js), Google Cloud Platform (App Engine).

Freelance/Self-employed

July 2012-August 2015

Web Developer

- · Developed websites, administered systems, and wrote technical content for blogs as a ghostwriter.
- · Technologies/Tools: Ubuntu Linux, Python (Flask), MySQL, JavaScript.

RECOGNITIONS

Red Hat - Several peer-to-peer awards from team members (including engineering) for collaboration and commitment to excellence.

Ribbon Communications - Motivate Award (2019-2020) for extraordinary performance.

Tata Elxsi - Customer Appreciation Award (2016-2017) based on client recommendation.

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Technology

2014